Register of the John Kenneth Caldwell papers
Hoover Institution Archives
John Kenneth Caldwell papers
1930-1978
76009
Hoover Institution Archives
1 folder, 1 envelope, 12 motion picture film reels (0.3 linear feet)
Memoirs, printed matter, and photographs relating to American foreign relations and commerce with Japan, Russia, Australia, China, and Ethiopia, 1906-1945, and to American participation in international narcotics control agencies; and motion picture film depicting scenes of daily life in China, 1930-1942. Digital copies of select records also available at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org.
Caldwell, John Kenneth, 1881-1982.
Access
Collection open for research.
Use copies of some motion picture film in this collection are available for immediate access; digital copies also available at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org. To view other films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1976.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Alternate Forms Available
Digital copies of select records also available at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org.
Biographical Note
American diplomat; consul, Vladivostok, Russia, 1914-1920; secretary of embassy to Japan, 1921-1924; chairman, United States delegation, Conference on the Limitation of the Manufacture of Narcotic Drugs, Geneva, 1931; consul general, Sydney, Australia, 1932-1935; consul general, Tientsin, China, 1935-1941; minister to Ethiopia, 1943-1945.
Scope and Content of Collection
Memoirs, printed matter, and photographs relating to American foreign relations and commerce with Japan, Russia, Australia, China, and Ethiopia, 1906-1945, and to American participation in international narcotics control agencies; and motion picture film depicting scenes of daily life in China, 1930-1942.
United States. Department of State.; Drug control; Soviet Union--History--Allied intervention, 1918-1920.; United States--Foreign relations.; Hoover, Herbert, 1874-1964.; World War, 1939-1945--Diplomatic history.; China--Pictorial works.; Diplomats--United States.; Motion pictures.
- Memoirs and printed matter (Folder 1)
- Motion picture film, 1930-1942 (Film shelf)
  Scope and Contents note
  The descriptions for the motion picture film reels are all taken from the intertitle cards that exist in each film and indicate the content that is contained in the motion picture film.
  - Peking - 16mm silent film, 1935-1942 (Reel 1)
    Intertitles
    The Gleaming Roofs of the Forbidden City Defy the Ravages of Time
    The Tombs of the King Emperors Lie Neglected in the Foothills
    The Summer Palace Remains Unspoiled Since the Days of the Empress Dowager
    Reflections: The Empress' Fish Pond
    A Splendid Panorama Rewards the Climber of Coal Hill
    The Camels Are Coming!
    To This Altar the Son of Heaven Went Yearly to Intercede for His People
    The Dragon Kings Were Wont to Enjoy Their Sports at the Winter Palace
    Like a Jewel Mirrored in the Ohunghai Lake
    The Sheltered Quiet of Chinese Houses Near Peking Still Provides Relief from the Strain of Diplomatic Life
    The Proud Disdain the Camels Carry on Regardless of Incidents and "New Orders"
    Persimmons Are on Sale Everywhere, Beside the Old Fortune Teller and at the Temple of Confucius
    The Feet of the Multitude and the North Wind Stir Up the Dust Outside the Hatamen Gate
    From the Tai Miao Stretches a Vista of Yellow Roofs to the Forbidden City
  - Conte Verde-Gripsholm; Shanghai-New York - 16mm silent film, 1942 (Reel 2)
    On the Conte Verde and Gripsholm evacuees from China reach N.Y. August 1942
    The long way home Shanghai to New York via Laurenco Marques on the Conte Verde and Gripsholm June 29 - August 25, 1942
  - Columbia Country Club, etc. - 16mm silent film, 1930-1936 (Reel 3)
    Access
    Use copy available on-site for immediate use. Use copy reference number: 76009_f_0009881.
    Note
    16mm reversal original, silent, edited, color. This film was preserved through a 2012 grant from the National Film Preservation Foundation.
    Columbia Country Club, August 1930 / Washington Cherries, Spring 1931
    Potomac Park and Tidal Basin
    Geneva Flower Festival, June 1931
    Bangkok, Wat Phra Keo (Temple of the Emerald Buddha), November 1931
    Poinsettias at "Tudor," Sydney, June 21, 1934
    House and Botanic Garden
    Tientsin Army Review
    Chinese Funeral in Tientsin, 1936
  - British Consulate in Washington, D.C.; skating in China - 16mm silent film, 1937-1938 (Reel 4)
    Coronation Illumination, Gordon Hall and Our Contribution [nighttime shots of buildings with lights]
    The Hollyhocks Bloom Despite Poor Soil at 71 Meadows Road
    The Soft Gray of Spanish Moss at Cypress Gardens
    Washington in Autumn
    Tientsin - Peking Hunt at Tientsin, February 1938
    Tientsin Winter Sports, Curling, Skating "P'ai Tsu"
    Madame Fuyet Demonstrates the Waltz
  - Life in Tientsin and Paitaiho - 16mm silent film, 1938 (Reel 5)
    The Guillaumes at the Country Club
    Departure of the 15th US Infantry from Tientsin
    Presentation by American Community at American Barracks
    International Guard of Honor at French Square
    En Route to the Station, March 2, 1938, Led by the British Band, Salute at American Consulate General
    Smoke of Farewell Fireworks at Victoria Park
    Arriving at East Station Led by the Italian Band
    The Marines Have Landed! Admiral Yarnell and Lt. Col. James, Inspection May 1938
    July 4, 1938, Review on "Can Do Field"
    At the Haesart's Tennis Court
    Summer Solace at the Solivas'
    The James and Orr Families After Ham and Eggs at the Grandstand
    Peitaiho 1938, "Pine Cliff"
    Dangerous Curves Ahead! On the Beach
  - Racing; flowers; peach blossoms in Tientsin - 16mm silent film, 1937-1938 (Reel 6)
    A Day at the Races in Tientsin [features horse races, rickshaw stand]
    Tientsin Hunt Club, Autumn Gymkhana, 27th November 1938
    War Fund Grand Football Match, Min Yuan Field, Sunday April 14th
    Peaches and Other Blossoms
  - Flood in China; Chinese funeral; farewell review Tientsin, China - 16mm silent film, 1939; 16mm reversal original, silent, edited, color and black & white (Reel 7)
    Use copy available on-site for immediate use. Use copy reference number: 76009_f_0009883.
    This film was preserved through a 2012 grant from the National Film Preservation Foundation.
  - Regatta, soccer, field days, fusiliers in Tientsin - 16mm silent film, 1937-1938 (Reel 8)
    Lancashire Fusiliers in Tientsin
    Navy Ship Departing
    French Field Day at East Arsenal
    Rowing Regatta on the Odoriferous Haiho, Soccer Game, April 1938
  - Polo; dogs; badminton in China - 16mm silent film, 1938-1939 (Reel 9)
    The Country Club, Winter Badmington [sic]
    I Can't Remember a Worse December, Just Watch These Icicles Form! Susan and Micky [dogs playing in snow]
    Spring, Building the Tennis Courts [Chinese laborers]
    Summer, Peking - Tientsin Polo Game, June 1938, The Club Gardens
    A Tientsin Summer, 1939, From Polo to Boating
    Place Your Bets! Your Money Will Move as Fast as the Hai Lai Players!
  - Boat picnic; scenery; war damage in Tientsin - 16mm silent film, 1937 (Reel 10)
    A Boat Picnic in Tientsin, June 1937
    Sea Lyons [sic] at Chinwangta, July 4, 1937
    The Old Swimming Hole at the Club
    The July 29th Incident at Tientsin, Shell Hole in Country Club Wall
    Morning's Corner, Barricade at British Concession Boundary, Refugee Boat Dwellers
    Yamen River, French Tank and Guard at International Bridge
    Haiho River from Ex-Russian Concession, Refugees and Corpses, August 1, 1937
    Tennis at the Recreation Ground, September 1937
    Tennis at Bruce's, 1937
    David and Lizette at the Club, October 5, 1937
  - Country Club Ball, departure of British, farewell ceremonies in Tientsin - 16mm silent film, 1939-1940 (Reel 11)
    The 1939 Tientsin Summer Sizzled Behind Barricades and Live Wire Fences as We Went Bowling Over Bumps and Humps
    Ring Out the Old, Ring in the New! Ready for the Country Club Fancy Dress Ball, New Year's Eve 1938
    In Preparation for the Tientsin Summer, the House Is Given Its Sheltering Straw Mat "P'eng" [Chinese laborers applying straw roof to house]
    The Consular Residence Serves as a Chapel for the Wedding of Lt. Schartzel of the US Marine Corps, Tientsin, March 1939
    The Interior of the Consular Residence Radiates Hospitality for Visiting Admirals and High Commissioners, May-June 1939
    The Last of the British Brigadiers, Sir John and Lady Laurie Depart, January 1940
    For Remembrance! Armistice Day 1938
  - San Francisco passage to Japan and China from Seattle; David in Japan; life in China - 16mm silent film, 1937 (Reel 12)
    This film was digitized by the California Audiovisual Preservation Project (CAVPP).
    From Mark Hopkins Hotel Roof, Fairmont and Mark Hopkins Hotels Down California Street
    The Bay Bridge, Alcatraz Island, Golden Gate Bridge Through the Fog
    After the Crash, Oil on Life Boat, Movie Tug, Back to the Pier, All Off the Ship [SS President Coolidge and oil tanker collided]
    Golden Gate Bridge, Frank H. Buck [oil tanker] and Ohio Aground Near Seal Rocks [sinking ship]
    En Route to Seattle, President Jackson, March 13, 1937, Victoria BC
    A Stormy Passage Nearing Yokohama on Deck in Kobe, A Cotton Lighter Burns
    Whangpoo River, Shanghai, March 31, Purple Mountain, Nanking
    American Consular Residence, The English Church, British Consular Residence
    The Lancashire Fusiliers Attend Church
    The Astor House, Tientsin Club, Keilan Building
    International Track Meet at Min Yuan Field
    International Guard of Honor on Colonel Lynch's Departure
- 1 print depicting the ceremony deposing the Governor of Vladivostok, 1917 March (Envelope A)